Sometimes when making multi-layered clothing, there will be unstable places.
In the clothing in this video, you can see that it is very unstable between the edge and the panel.
For this kind of clothing, we need to use several functions.
Reverse fire, freeze, hardening
To make it easier for each panel, turn on random colors first.
This dress mainly has three panels, a large dress panel and two cross-stitches.
Use the editor to see the relationship between the two panels.
There is a cross-stitch that is all combined with the outer line of the side panel of the dress.
The other panel is on top of these two panels and belongs to the outer structure.
When the clothing is multi-layered, we usually deal with conflicts from the inside to the outside.
So at this time, I chose the most complete cross-stitch and prepared to reverse fire them.
When a panel is reversed, it will no longer participate in the simulation and will not collide with other panels.
There are two options for reverse fire. One is to reverse fire the sewing line and the panel.
The other option is to reverse fire only the panel.
Here, select the panel and the sewing line to reverse fire.
In this way, the sewing line between the panels will not have any effect.
After opening the simulation, you can see that the unstable place before is now stable.
After changing the perspective, you can see that the position of the pleats is very close to the panel and the panel.
When the panel and the panel are very close to each other,
if you use the add function directly to arrange the panel, it may be unstable.
Now the conflict thickness between the panels is 1, which is too close.
Adjusting to 2.5 can make the distance between the panels farther.
Now switch back to the thick texture surface.
Select these panels on the inner layer.
When the panel is hardened, its bending strength will be increased.
The fold of the fabric becomes very large.
The panel will also be opened a little.
After opening, using the add function will be more stable and easier to deal with future problems.
Then you can remove the hardening.
In order to maintain the shape of these panels and keep them in contact with the edge of the outer layer, they still need to be frozen.
You can see that after opening the simulation, these panels will not participate in the simulation.
They will be frozen in the 3D window.
In the 2D window, select the hidden edge.
Then press Shift-Q to display them.
Then restart them.
After restarting, select Add to the outside.
In this way, the panel will automatically move to the outer layer according to the powder line.
Then press Shift-Q to display them.
At this time, when the simulation is started, you will find that this edge of the contract will still be unstable.
First, apply layer 1 to this edge without application layer.
After applying layer, simulate.
The high layer will automatically simulate the outer layer of the lower layer.
Unlock the white panel.
Change the body to the back to check the earth face of the material.
Once the material is on the surface, the back of the material will be solid black.
zamfind .
Take a look at this area.
This is the problem with this area, so we have to do some processing on it, otherwise it will be more difficult to correctly identify when opening the simulation.
First of all, when these two plates have entered the skirt through the layer to the outer layer, the layer will need to return to zero.
After the layer returns to zero, the simulation will not be as unstable as it was when preserving the layer.
Then we have to process this piece through to the back of the fabric.
First of all, we click on this piece of fabric in the 3D window.
After clicking, a small blue dot will appear in the 3D and 2D windows at the same time.
Then select the selection grid tool, click near the blue dot in the 2D window and drag the mouse to select a part of the grid.
After selecting, click on the selected area again to drag the axis of the positioning ball.
Then click on the selected area to adjust the grid position.
When selecting the grid, try not to select too much at once, so that there will always be penetrations when adjusting with the positioning ball.
For the less selected grid, use the positioning ball to pull them out.
After starting the simulation, the grid that was pulled out will simulate correctly, and then you can deal with the other parts of the grid.
After processing, you can manually drag the edge of the grid to make it fit the inner layer of the skirt.
Now look at this edge of the grid, you will find that the front part is already stable on the outside.
Then we can fix this part first.
Then click on the selection grid tool and select the same tool in the menu.
Whether it is the selection grid or the positioning ball, if it is drawn directly in the 3D window, it will select all visible grids.
Therefore, the one on the back will also be selected.
Therefore, it is recommended to select the grid and add a fixing pin in the 2D window.
When selecting tools, there are two types of comparison and set-up. The former is to select the area of ​​the frame, and the latter is to freely create an area.
After starting the simulation, these areas with the fixing pin will be fixed in the 3D environment.
Then activate the frozen contract edge panel.
We can see that the part where the skirt is placed will be very close. In this case, it is not convenient to adjust the selection grid.
If the contract edge is frozen, there is no way to change the shape of the skirt, and it will always follow the frozen contract edge.
After starting the simulation, the skirt will still be very soft and unstable.
At this time, select all the plates that form the skirt and print them, so that the skirt is larger and the frame is larger.
During this time, you can manually adjust the position, so that there is enough space between the folds.
Then continue to freeze the contract edge to control the overall shape.
Activate the inner panel.
Select the grid in the 2D window and move these grids in the 3D window.
If the grid is still in the previous position after opening the simulation, you can first convert the selected grid to the fixing pin.
Select some grids and move them to the fixing pin.
Then open the simulation and apply the changes.
Then repeat this step. During this time, you must simulate the application changes.
You can see that the last small piece has been stable and worn to the outside.
Then you can delete the fixing pin and start the simulation.
At this time, the entire grid of the contract edge is already on the outside, and it will not be worn in again.
Then you can delete the existing fixing pin before creating it.
Harden the contract edge of this outer layer and attach the skirt to the inner layer.
After the whole is stable, you can move the inner layer contract edge together.
Let's simulate the other side of the contract edge together.
Let's simulate it first. If it is stable, immediately stop the simulation and finish the hardening process.
During the simulation process, you can continuously press the control button to start or stop the simulation.
Continue to simulate. If there is an unstable place, immediately stop the simulation.
Then you can go back to the previous time to stop the simulation and check where the clothing is unstable.
First of all, the conflict thickness of the outer contract edge is not modified to 2.5.
Therefore, when selecting the two black sides, a red line appears.
Therefore, the conflict thickness will be modified to 2.5 and the particle diameter will be reduced to 10.
If you simulate it again, you can see that it is stable.
At this time, there is an unstable place above, so stop the simulation and simulate it again.
It turned out to be temporarily unstable.
In order to prevent further instability, select this version and reduce the particle diameter to 10 and continue to simulate.
In addition, there is a place to deal with.
Now the two contract edges are integrated on the group board, and they are all custom angle properties, which will cause them to collide.
The cross-sectional line between the contract edge and the group board on the lower layer will be integrated on the inner layer of the contract edge.
After integration, the type of cross-sectional line will be changed to Turned.
After changing to Turned, it will be identified as two contract edges overlapping each other, and it will not be easy to have instability.
After stabilization, the particle diameter can be increased to 20, and there will be no instability.
Then you can deal with other unstable places. See you in the next video.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community